A Guide to the Nelson A. Rockefeller personal papers, Activities, Series A FA338
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Contributions by NAR, 1930-1972
  - Annual Schedules of Giving Since 1930, 1949-1961 (Box 62, Folder 520)
    Annual reports on NAR's giving prepared by Dana S. Creel. Summary figures for the period 1930-1969.
  - Annual Schedules of Giving Since 1930, 1949-1961 (Box 62, Folder 521)
  - Memoranda, 1937-1964, 1967, 1970 (Box 62, Folder 522)
    Inter-office memos re: NAR's overall giving program.
  - Memoranda, 1937-1964, 1967, 1970 (Box 62, Folder 523)
  - Memoranda, 1937-1964, 1967, 1970 (Box 62, Folder 524)
  - Memoranda, 1937-1964, 1967, 1970 (Box 62, Folder 525)
  - Memoranda, 1937-1964, 1967, 1970 (Box 62, Folder 526)
  - AIA, 1946-1970 (Box 62, Folder 527)
    Correspondence re: NAR's gifts of stock and money; pledges.
  - AIA, 1946-1970 (Box 62, Folder 528)
  - AIA and IRI, 1952, 1956 (Box 62, Folder 529)
    Memos re: financial needs of American International Association for Social and Economic Development and International Basic Economy Corporation Research Institute; NAR contributions.
  - Albany, NY, Philanthropies - Correspondence (A-I), 1960-1969 (Box 62, Folder 530)
    NAR contributions to various Albany organizations, institutions and projects.
  - Albany, NY, Philanthropies - Correspondence (J-U), 1959-1972 (Box 63, Folder 531)
  - Albany, NY, Philanthropies - Correspondence (J-U), 1959-1972 (Box 63, Folder 532)
  - Albany, NY, Philanthropies - Inter-office Memoranda, 1959-1960 (Box 63, Folder 533)
  - Educational Gift Matching Program, 1963, 1965-1966, 1968-1971 (Box 63, Folder 534)
    Rockefeller family office meets employees gifts to schools.
  - IBEC, 1947-1949, 1952, 1956 (Box 63, Folder 535)
    Correspondence re: contributions; subscriptions to stock. NAR letter to his brothers on subscription to stock. Accounting of stock held by Rockefellers, 1947.
  - IBEC, ITSC - Gifts of Stock, 1947-1952 (Box 63, Folder 536)
    Correspondence re: NAR's gift of stock to friends. Memo re: charitable gifts of stock.
  - IBEC Research Institute (IRI), 1950-1965 (Box 63, Folder 537)
    Correspondence re: gifts of stock; pledges; contributions; housing program in Brazil; merging of IKI with AIA, 1957.
  - Program Relating to New York, 1959-1960 (Box 63, Folder 538)
    Memos on structure of NAR's giving program for New York.
  - Donations, 1958-1969 (Box 63, Folder 539)
    Correspondence re: donations of objects for benefit auctions; miscellaneous contributions; contribution program, 1960-1966.
  - Pledges, 1958-1972 (Box 63, Folder 540)
    Arranged alphabetically.
- Contributions by NAR, Political, 1946-1971
  NAR contributions to various Republican organizations and Republican committees and candidates.
  - Memoranda, 1946-1963 (Box 63, Folder 541)
    Recommendations from NAR's associates on contributions to Republican candidates.
  - General Correspondence (A-H), 1946-1971 (Box 63, Folder 542)
  - General Correspondence (I-Y), 1946-1971 (Box 64, Folder 543)
  - General Correspondence (I-Y), 1946-1971 (Box 64, Folder 544)
  - General Correspondence (I-Y), 1946-1971 (Box 64, Folder 545)
  - General Correspondence (I-Y), 1946-1971 (Box 64, Folder 546)
  - General Correspondence (I-Y), 1946-1971 (Box 64, Folder 547)
  - General Correspondence (I-Y), 1946-1971 (Box 64, Folder 548)
  - Miscellaneous Donations, 1958-1971 (Box 64, Folder 549)
    NAR contributions to Republican organizations, political events, and benefits for Republican organizations.
  - Miscellaneous Donations, 1958-1971 (Box 64, Folder 550)
  - Miscellaneous Donations, 1958-1971 (Box 64, Folder 551)
  - Special Donations, 1946-1970
    - Eisenhower Campaign Committees, 1952-1963 (Box 65, Folder 552)
    - Maine Republican Finance Committee, 1948-1968 (Box 65, Folder 553)
    - National Republican Congressional Committee, 1946-1959, 1962 (Box 65, Folder 554)
    - National Republican Senatorial Committee, 1946-1948, 1954, 1956, 1960-1968 (Box 65, Folder 555)
    - New York Republican State Committee, 1947-1968 (Box 65, Folder 556)
    - New York Young Republican Club, 1956-1969 (Box 65, Folder 557)
    - Ninth District Republican Club, 1960-1965 (Box 65, Folder 558)
    - Republican County Committee of the County of New York, 1946-1965 (Box 65, Folder 559)
    - Republican National Committee, 1946-1968 (Box 65, Folder 560)
    - United Republican Finance Committee (NY State), 1947-1965 (Box 66, Folder 561)
    - Westchester County Republican Committee, 1948-1970 (Box 66, Folder 562)
    - Westchester County Republican Committee, 1948-1970 (Box 66, Folder 563)
- Creole Petroleum
  NAR a minority stockholder on the board of directors. Approximately 80% of Creole stock owned by Standard Oil of New Jersey. Correspondence re: NAR stock purchase; strikes in 1936 and 1937; reports to directors, Seaview conference. NAR resigned in August 1940 when he was appointed Coordinator of Inter-American Affairs.
  - 1935-1942 (Box 66, Folder 564)
  - 1946-1947 (Box 66, Folder 565)
  - 1952, 1954 (Box 66, Folder 566)
  - 1956, 1959 (Box 66, Folder 567)
- Directorships Held by NAR, 1948-1949, 1952, 1956, 1963 (Box 66, Folder 568)
  List of NAR directorships, 1963. Invitations to join boards.
- Economics Group - Memoranda, 1957-1958, 1960, 1966 (Box 66, Folder 569)
- Economics Group - Reports, 1947 (Box 67, Folder 570)
- Economics Group - Reports, 1949 (Box 67, Folder 571)
- Economics Group - Reports, 1952 (Box 67, Folder 572)
- Economics Group - Reports, 1958 (Box 67, Folder 573)
- Entertainment
  - General Files, 1959-1971 (Box 67, Folder 574)
    Plans for miscellaneous dinners and affairs, menus, letters of thanks, replies to invitations, NAR's purchase of tickets to miscellaneous dinners, arrangements for Rockefeller family Christmas lunch at NAR's home, 812 Fifth Ave., 1965.
  - General Files, 1959-1971 (Box 67, Folder 0574A)
  - General Files, 1959-1971 (Box 67, Folder 575)
  - General Files, 1959-1971 (Box 67, Folder 0575A)
  - Arrangements and Procedures, 1953-1971 (Box 67, Folder 576)
    General instructions for dinner arrangements, traffic and security plans at Pocantico, Governor's Club receptions.
  - Arrangements and Procedures, 1953-1971 (Box 67, Folder 0576A)
  - Deming Co., Inc., 1959-1969 (Box 67, Folder 577)
    Supplied tents for entertainments at Pocantico Hills.
  - 810 Business Dinners, 1961 (Box 67, Folder 578)
    List of business leaders NAR should meet with to explain his philosophy and objectives, list of those invited to dinner at NAR's home at 810 Fifth Ave.
  - Inner Circle Dinner, 1933-1968 (Box 67, Folder 579)
    Organization of New York Political Writers annual dinner, NAR's purchase of tickets, 1959, 1962-1964, 1966-1968.
  - Invitations, Sample, 1959 (Box 67, Folder 580)
    Samples of engraved invitations.
  - Invitations Accepted by NAR, 1966 (Box 67, Folder 581)
    List of accepted invitations, January - July, 1966.
  - Legislative Correspondents Association, 1966-1971 (Box 67, Folder 582)
    Luncheons, dinners, menus, entertainment, guest lists.
  - Lists, 1946-1971 (Box 67, Folder 583)
    Guest lists and seating arrangements for miscellaneous events.
  - Lists, 1946-1971 (Box 67, Folder 0583A)
  - Lists, 1946-1971 (Box 68, Folder 584)
  - Lists, 1946-1971 (Box 68, Folder 0584A)
  - Lists, 1946-1971 (Box 68, Folder 585)
  - Lists, 1946-1971 (Box 68, Folder 0585A)
  - Lists, 1946-1971 (Box 68, Folder 586)
  - Lists, 1946-1971 (Box 68, Folder 0586A)
  - Special Events (Box 68, Folder 587)
    Arrangements and guest lists for the following special events: Pres. and Mrs. Medici (Brazil), 12/9/71 Kay Graham, 11/71 2500 Foxhall, President's Foreign Intelligence Advisory Board, 10/21/71 Advisory Committee on Intergovernmental Relations, 10/8/71 Pocantico Hills, 9/22/71 Chase Manhattan Bank Party, 12/19/71 Governor's Club Reception, 9/17/71 Informal Stag Dinner, 812 Fifth Ave., 7/26/71 Dr. Franklin D. Murphy, 4/29/71 Election Night Party, 11/03/70
  - Special Events (Box 68, Folder 0587A)
    Arrangements and guest lists for the following special events: Family Christmas Luncheon, 12/19/71 Happy Rockefeller Tea, 4/14/71
  - Special Events (Box 68, Folder 588)
    Arrangements and guest lists for the following special events: Publisher's Dinner, 10/24/70
  - Special Events (Box 68, Folder 0588A)
  - Special Events (Box 68, Folder 589)
    Arrangements and guest lists for the following special events: United Nations Reception, New York State Theater, 10/19/70
  - Special Events (Box 68, Folder 590)
  - Special Events (Box 68, Folder 0590A)
  - Special Events (Box 69, Folder 591)
  - Special Events (Box 69, Folder 592)
  - Special Events (Box 69, Folder 593)
  - Special Events (Box 69, Folder 594)
  - Special Events (Box 69, Folder 595)
    Arrangements and guest lists for the following special events: Entertainment for NAR, 10/6/70 Victor d'Amico Party, 6/23/70 Dinner before A.F.I. Benefit, 5/27/70 Columbus Citizens Committee Reception, 4/23/70
  - Special Events (Box 69, Folder 0595A)
  - Special Events (Box 69, Folder 596)
    Arrangements and guest lists for the following special events: Dinner, 812 Fifth Ave., 12/22/69 Dinner, Election Night, 11/4/69 Reception for Mrs. Charles Payson and N.Y. Mets, 10/8/69
  - Special Events (Box 69, Folder 597)
    Arrangements and guest lists for the following special events: Governor's Club Reception, 9/24/69 New York State Council on the Arts, 8/28/69
  - Special Events (Box 69, Folder 598)
    Arrangements and guest lists for the following special events: Dinner for D. Miller, 6/11/69 Luncheon for South American Ambassadors, 6/10/69 Dinner for Mr. and Mrs. Bob Hope, 6/4/69 MoMA Reception, 5/27/69 Metropolitan Museum of Art, 5/8/69 Dinner - Viscount and Viscountess, 4/16/69
  - Special Events (Box 69, Folder 0598A)
  - Special Events (Box 70, Folder 599)
    Arrangements and guest lists for the following special events: Reception, Society of Foreign Consuls, 12/17/68 Election Night Party, 11/5/68
  - Special Events (Box 70, Folder 0599A)
  - Special Events (Box 70, Folder 600)
    Arrangements and guest lists for the following special events: Governor's Club, 9/26/68 Rene d'Harnoncourt, 6/11/68
  - Special Events (Box 70, Folder 601)
    Arrangements and guest lists for the following special events: King of Norway, 5/10/68 Dinner, 812 Fifth Avenue, 4/3/68 Mr. and Mrs. Max Fisher, 2/7/68
  - Special Events (Box 70, Folder 0601A)
  - Special Events (Box 70, Folder 602)
    Arrangements and guest lists for the following special events: Governor's Conference Barbecue, 6/30/67
  - Special Events (Box 70, Folder 603)
    Arrangements and guest lists for the following special events: Dinner-Dance, Pocantico Hills, 6/09/67
  - Special Events (Box 70, Folder 604)
  - Special Events (Box 70, Folder 0604A)
    Arrangements and guest lists for the following special events: Dinner-Dance replies, Pocantico Hills, 6/09/67
  - Special Events (Box 70, Folder 605)
  - Special Events (Box 70, Folder 0605A)
  - Special Events (Box 70, Folder 606)
  - Special Events (Box 70, Folder 0606A)
    Arrangements and guest lists for the following special events: Dinner-Dance, Pocantico Hills, 6/09/67. Replies.
  - Special Events (Box 71, Folder 607)
  - Special Events (Box 71, Folder 608)
  - Special Events (Box 71, Folder 609)
  - Special Events (Box 71, Folder 610)
  - Special Events - Oversized Material (Box 71A)
  - Special Events (Box 72, Folder 611)
    Arrangements and guest lists for the following special events: Dinner-Dance, Pocantico Hills, Card File, 6/09/67
  - Special Events (Box 73, Folder 612)
    Arrangements and guest lists for the following special events: Dinner and Canadian Centennial Ball, 5/05/67 President and Senora Frei Dinner, 2/05/67
  - Special Events (Box 73, Folder 613)
    Arrangements and guest lists for the following special events: Election Night Dinner, 11/8/66 Reception, Election Staff and Campaign People, 11/6/66 Westchester Press Association Breakfast, 9/27/66 Dinner for Ambassador H.E. Enrique Tejera - Paris, 5/24/66
  - Special Events (Box 73, Folder 614)
    Arrangements and guest lists for the following special events: Reception, Council for the Arts in Westchester, 4/23/66 Dinner - Steven Clark Rockefeller and Friends, 3/3/66
  - Special Events (Box 73, Folder 615)
    Arrangements and guest lists for the following special events: Family Christmas Luncheon, 12/19/65 Dinner in Honor of Hon. and Mrs. Goldberg, 11/8/65 Election Night Party, 11/2/65
  - Special Events (Box 73, Folder 616)
    Arrangements and guest lists for the following special events: United Nations Secretary General U. Thant Dinner, 5/26/65 Reception, Consular Corps., 5/20/65 Dinner, 812 Fifth Ave., 4/8/65
  - Special Events (Box 73, Folder 617)
    Arrangements and guest lists for the following special events: Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr. Luncheon, 812 Fifth Ave., 12/18/64 Dinner - Jay C. Leff, 812 Fifth Ave., 11/23/64
  - Special Events (Box 73, Folder 618)
    Arrangements and guest lists for the following special events: Reception, Chief State School Officers, 11/18/64 Dinner, Princess Laetitia Boncampagni, 11/3/64 Pocantico Hills Party, Albany Press, 7/2/64 Counsel's Dinner, 4/24/64
  - Special Events (Box 73, Folder 619)
    Arrangements and guest lists for the following special events: Dinner, New York State Theater Opening, 4/23/64 Reception for M. Legendre, 3/23/64
  - Special Events (Box 74, Folder 620)
    Arrangements and guest lists for the following special events: Buffet, Westchester Co. Committee, 10/15/63 Luncheon, Pres. R. Betancourt
  - Special Events (Box 74, Folder 621)
    Arrangements and guest lists for the following special events: Election Night, 11/6/62 New York State Council on the Arts, 8/26/62
  - Special Events (Box 74, Folder 622)
    Arrangements and guest lists for the following special events: Pres. Joao Goulart, 4/5/62
  - Special Events (Box 74, Folder 623)
    Arrangements and guest lists for the following special events: Jacob Javits, 4/7/62
  - Special Events (Box 74, Folder 624)
    Arrangements and guest lists for the following special events: Inter-American Press Association, 10/13/61
  - Special Events (Box 74, Folder 625)
  - Special Events (Box 75, Folder 626)
    Arrangements and guest lists for the following special events: Tea, General and Mrs. Chen Cheng
  - Special Events (Box 75, Folder 627)
    Arrangements and guest lists for the following special events: Reception, Society of Foreign Consuls, 1/27/61
  - Special Events (Box 75, Folder 628)
  - Special Events (Box 75, Folder 629)
    Arrangements and guest lists for the following special events: Dinner, R. Wieglus, 11/22/60 King and Queen of Denmark, 10/16/60
  - Special Events (Box 75, Folder 630)
    Arrangements and guest lists for the following special events: King of Thailand Dinner, 7/4/60
  - Special Events (Box 75, Folder 631)
  - Special Events (Box 75, Folder 632)
    Arrangements and guest lists for the following special events: Pres. Lleras Camargo, 4/11/60
  - Special Events (Box 76, Folder 633)
    Arrangements and guest lists for the following special events: Dr. V. Belaunde, 11/6/59
  - Special Events (Box 76, Folder 634)
    Arrangements and guest lists for the following special events: United Nations Party, 10/10/59, (Cancelled)
  - Special Events (Box 76, Folder 635)
    Arrangements and guest lists for the following special events: H.R.H. Princess Beatrix, 9/18-19/59
  - Special Events (Box 76, Folder 636)
  - Special Events (Box 76, Folder 637)
    Arrangements and guest lists for the following special events: King Baudouin of the Belgians, Dinner, 5/29/59
  - Special Events (Box 76, Folder 638)
  - Special Events (Box 77, Folder 639)
    Arrangements and guest lists for the following special events: New York Legislators, 4/17/59 Dona Sara Kubitschek, 4/12/59
  - Special Events (Box 77, Folder 640)
    Arrangements and guest lists for the following special events: Pres. Sean O'Kelly
  - Special Events (Box 77, Folder 641)
    Arrangements and guest lists for the following special events: Pres. Jose Maria Lemus, 3/15/59
  - Special Events (Box 77, Folder 642)
    Arrangements and guest lists for the following special events: Election Night, 11/4/58 MoMA Seurat Exhibition Dinner, 3/24/58 Links Club Dinner, 3/3/58
  - Special Events (Box 77, Folder 643)
    Arrangements and guest lists for the following special events: Brazilian Press, 10/22/57 Salute to Arts dinner, 10/10/57 Metropolitan Museum of Art, Puerto Rico Films, 10/9/57 Metropolitan Museum of Art, Picasso Exhibit, 5/20/57 Luncheon, Brazilian Delegates, 2/6/57
  - Special Events (Box 77, Folder 644)
    Arrangements and guest lists for the following special events: Metropolitan Museum of Art, Recent Acquisitions Exhibition, 11/26/56 Vice-Pres. of Brazil, Joao Goulart, 5/17/56 Dr. and Mrs. Detlev W. Bronk, 5/15/56 Dinner Before Gonzalez Show, 2/6/56 Washington, D.C. Staff Dinner, 1/17/56
  - Special Events (Box 77, Folder 645)
    Arrangements and guest lists for the following special events: Mr. and Mrs. Rene d'Harnoncourt, 1/26/54
  - Special Events (Box 77, Folder 646)
    Arrangements and guest lists for the following special events: Knickerbocker Club, New York City, 6/9/53 Rockefeller Center Executives Outing, 6/5/53 Luncheon, 4/23/53 Metropolitan Museum of Art, E. G. Robinson Show, 3/3/53 Maria Martins, 2/16/53 A. H. Sulzberger, 1/14/53
  - Special Events (Box 77, Folder 647)
    Arrangements and guest lists for the following special events: Entertainment - Washington, D.C., 1953-56 Lists of Possible Guests, 1953-55 Secretary and Mrs. Perkins, 4/14/54 Richard M. Nixon, 6/5/54 Speaker of the House, Martin, 6/23/54 Senator Bowring, 5/18/54 Russell R. Larmon, 7/14/54 Kajhumari, Amrit Kaur, 10/6/54 Sweater Group, 5/12/55
  - Special Events (Box 78, Folder 648)
    Arrangements and guest lists for the following special events: Dartmouth '30 Executive Committee, 10/31/52 United Nations Dinner, 10/23/52 Metropolitan Museum of Art, Les Fauves Exhibit Dinner, 10/7/52
  - Special Events (Box 78, Folder 649)
    Arrangements and guest lists for the following special events: Rockefeller Center Executives Outing, 5/23/52
  - Special Events (Box 78, Folder 650)
    Arrangements and guest lists for the following special events: Metropolitan Museum of Art Committee in Art Education Dinner, 3/21/52 UNESCO Reception, Rainbow Room, 1/28/52
  - Special Events (Box 78, Folder 651)
    Arrangements and guest lists for the following special events: John Davison Rockefeller, Jr. Luncheon, Music Hall, 12/19/51 Metropolitan Museum of Art - Thursday Evening Club Party, 12/6/51 Dinner, 11/13/51 Dartmouth '30 Executive Committee, 11/2/51 Ensor Exhibit Opening, 9/25/51 Galo Plaza, 6/24/51 Horacio Lafer Luncheon, 6/22/51
  - Special Events (Box 78, Folder 652)
    Arrangements and guest lists for the following special events: Rockefeller Center Executives Outing, 5/25/51 Dinner, 810 Fifth Ave., 4/12/51 Metropolitan Museum of Art - Modigliani Preview, 4/9/51
  - Special Events (Box 78, Folder 653)
    Arrangements and guest lists for the following special events: Ministers of Foreign Affairs Luncheon, Sulgrave Club, Washington D.C., 4/2/51
  - Special Events (Box 78, Folder 654)
  - Special Events (Box 79, Folder 655)
    Arrangements and guest lists for the following special events: Mayor's Reception Committee, Dinner - Pres. Auriol, 4/2/51 Metropolitan Museum of Art Committee on Art Education, 3/16/51 Metropolitan Museum of Art - Abstract Art Opening, 1/23/51 Mr. and Mrs. John, Sr., Jr., Music Hall Dinner, 1/22/51 Dr. Antonio Martin Araujo Luncheon, 1/22/51 ABID - Luncheon, Dinner, 1950-51
  - Special Events (Box 79, Folder 656)
    Arrangements and guest lists for the following special events: Dr. Paulo Bittencourt, 12/7/50 Dr. Lucas Noggueiro Garez, 12/1/50 Clee, Gilbert, 11/8/50 Metropolitan Museum of Art - Soutine Show, 10/31/50 International Colloquium on Luso - Brazilian Studies, 10/24/50
  - Special Events (Box 79, Folder 657)
    Arrangements and guest lists for the following special events: Inter-American Press Conference and Reception, 10/13/50
  - Special Events (Box 79, Folder 658)
    Arrangements and guest lists for the following special events: Dinner in Honor of the Chairman of the Delegations to the 5th Session of the United Nations General Assembly, 10/5/50
  - Special Events (Box 79, Folder 659)
    Chairman of the Delegations Dinner, 10/5/50, Lists and Seating Arrangements
  - Special Events (Box 79, Folder 660)
    Chairman of the Delegations Dinner, 10/5/50, Acceptance Letters
  - Special Events (Box 79, Folder 661)
    Chairman of the Delegations Dinner, 10/5/50, Regret Letters
  - Special Events (Box 80, Folder 662)
    Arrangements and guest lists for the following special events: W. Averell Harriman, 9/28/50 Ambassador Norman Armour, 9/21/50 United Nations Dinner - Waldorf, 9/21/50 Dr. Alberto Lleras, 9/20/50
  - Special Events (Box 80, Folder 663)
    Arrangements and guest lists for the following special events: Aldrich Family Lunch, 6/24/50 Office of Messrs. Rockefeller, 6/16/50 Rockefeller Center Executive Outing, 6/3/50 Mr. and Mrs. Mario Marini, 5/30/50 Pan American Society of United States, for Pres. Gonzalez Videla, 4/18/50
  - Special Events (Box 80, Folder 664)
    Arrangements and guest lists for the following special events: President of Chile, Gonzalez Videla, 4/16/50
  - Special Events (Box 80, Folder 665)
    Arrangements and guest lists for the following special events: Mr. and Mrs. Oreamuno, 3/28/50 Venezuelan Trade Mission, 3/9/50 International Bank for Reconstruction and Development, 2/11/50 Thursday Evening Club, 1/25/50 Dr. and Mme. Jose T. Nabuco, 1/12/50
  - Guest Lists, 1949-1951, 1953 (Box 80, Folder 666)
  - Guest Lists, 1949-1951, 1953 (Box 80, Folder 667)
  - Guest Lists, 1949-1951, 1953 (Box 80, Folder 668)
  - Guest Lists, 1946-1949 (Box 81, Folder 669)
  - Guest Lists, 1946-1949 (Box 81, Folder 670)
  - Guest Lists, 1946-1949 (Box 81, Folder 671)
  - Guest Lists, 1946-1949 (Box 81, Folder 672)
  - Guest Lists, 1946-1949 (Box 81, Folder 673)
  - Guest Lists, 1935-1946 (Box 82, Folder 674)
  - Guest Lists, 1935-1946 (Box 82, Folder 675)
  - Guest Lists, 1935-1946 (Box 82, Folder 676)
- Foundations, 1952 (Box 82, Folder 677)
  Re: filing reports with U.S. Treasury Dept. Correspondence with Congressman Jacob K. Javits re: further filing regulations on foundations. Long interesting memo from John E. Lockwood on the regulation of charities.
- Gifts from NAR
  Gifts from NAR to various associates, friends, family members, employees, acquaintances, and memorial funds. Made in the form of money, medical care, items, memberships, and artwork.
  - Gifts from NAR, General, 1946-1971 (Box 82, Folder 678)
  - Gifts from NAR, General, 1946-1971 (Box 82, Folder 679)
  - Gifts from NAR, General, 1946-1971 (Box 82, Folder 680)
  - Gifts from NAR, General, 1946-1971 (Box 82, Folder 681)
  - Gifts from NAR - Ademuwagun, Zaccaeus Aki and Brother, 1963-1964 (Box 82, Folder 682)
    Two students NAR aided to study in the United States and Nigeria.
  - Gifts from NAR - Key Rings, 1966-1967 (Box 83, Folder 683)
    Gift to 1966 gubernatorial campaign workers. Lists and acknowledgements.
  - Gifts from NAR - Key Rings, 1966-1967 (Box 83, Folder 684)
  - Gifts from NAR - Key Rings, 1966-1967 (Box 83, Folder 685)
  - Gifts from NAR - Museums, 1952-1961 (Box 83, Folder 686)
    Correspondence re: NAR's gifts of art to museums; arrangement for Carlebach Galleries to purchase primitive art to be given to museums on behalf of NAR.
  - Gifts from NAR - Royalty and VIP, Gifts to, 1950-1970 (Box 83, Folder 687)
    Correspondence and photos re: items given, mostly Steuben glass figures; arrangements for delivery; inscriptions on some gifts; acknowledgements.
  - Gifts from NAR - Royalty and VIP, Gifts to, 1950-1970 (Box 83, Folder 688)